Bret Petersen

Full Stack Web & VR Developer

Minneapolis, MN 55404 (willing to relocate) • 415.939.1779 • <u>bretpetersen@gmail.com</u> <u>bretpetersen.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/bret-petersen/</u> • <u>github.com/bretpeters3n</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in visual design who enjoys the fast-paced environment of the tech industry and being part of pioneering teams. VR-fluent developer who enjoys creating interaction and animation filled mobile and desktop experiences.

Core Competencies and Skills: Full Stack Web Developer with a focus on Front End and VR.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Unity, AltspaceVR, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, Express, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Responsive Design, ORM, MVC, ES6, Git, Unit Testing, Snapshot Testing.

PROJECTS

Beautiful Mind VR App

Served as project lead while developing a VR application to teach ADHD users important life skills. *Tools used:* Unity, C#, SketchFab, Blender, NovelAl, Miro, and Premiere Pro. github.com/bretpeters3n/BMind vrUNITYApp • oculus.com/experiences/guest/6396613747021856/

Budgety

Acted as project lead in developing an application allowing users to create budgets and organize their funds. *Tools used:* Nest JS, Typescript, MongoDB, Bcrypt, Passport-JWT, GitHub, and GitHub Pages. github.com/bretpeters3n/seal-team-3 • https://budgetv-front.uc.r.appspot.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Web Developer and Designer • Coolibar, St. Louis Park, MN

02/2022 - current

- Updated e-commerce website with redesigned site navigation and new company logo.
- Increased accessibility of Magento site by conforming to current web standards.

Key achievement: Introduced use of video for collection releases.

UX/UI Designer • Irish Titan, St. Louis Park, MN

03/2020 - 06/2021

- Communicated with clients to discover their needs and fine tune their projects.
- Researched and tested e-commerce apps for use on our client's online stores.

Key achievement: Expedited adoption of Figma as the main software design tool.

Web Specialist • United Healthcare, Hopkins, MN

08/2019 - 12/2019

- · Animated advertisements and designed emails.
- Helped usher in more efficient email coding with the use of templates.

Key achievement: Received 'Employee of the Month' honor.

Web Animator • Target, Minneapolis, MN

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Created animated advertisements while working alongside a team of designers and developers.
- Introduced 3D animation into advertisements to increase their noticeability.

Key achievement: Facilitated faster workflow using Hype as main animation software.

Lead Web Designer & Web Animator • San Francisco, CA

10/2005 - 04/2018

Worked at Organic Inc, AKQA, among other agencies while working my way up to Lead Designer.

- Participated in conceptual brainstorming, designed out concepts, and animated ads based on concepts.
- Responsible for designing websites, creating style guides, working within brand guidelines.

EDUCATION

<u>== 0 0 1 11 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 </u>	
Unity, World Building, VR App Dev, and VR App Publishing Certificates • Universe (online)	2022
Full Stack Web Development Certificate • University of Minnesota	2021
UX Certificate • Brainco (Minneapolis, MN)	2019
Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design • University of Minnesota Duluth	2005